<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Python User Group Singapore</title><link>/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>October 2017 meetup</title><link>/2017-oct-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date:&lt;/em&gt; October 25, 7 to 9pm&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Venue:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.zendesk.com/"&gt;Zendesk&lt;/a&gt;, 401 Commonwealth Drive Haw Par Technocentre, #07-01
(&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/NNHUz"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Signup:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/243967771/"&gt;meetup
page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7pm: Meet &amp;amp; Greet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30pm: NLTK and Friends by Liling Tan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk will be a basic crash course to Natural Language Processing (NLP). We
will try to build a simple application in 30 minutes using NLTK and friends
(Scikit-Learn, SpaCy, Gensim and maybe, just maybe PyTorch)
[&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/cg7iza"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/alvations/basic-nlp-with-nltk/"&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://21.co/alvations/"&gt;Liling&lt;/a&gt; is a data geek who works mostly with text
processing and machine translation. He contributes to NLTK and seeks help from
StackOverflow whenever he works with Pandas dataframe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:00pm: Introduction to AWS Lambda with Python by Maximilian Jackson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Max is a regular visitor of our monthly user group meetups and has been an
active member of the Python User Group and an organizer of PyCon APAC and PyCon
Singapore for years. He has recently had the need to figure out how to deploy
Python functions to AWS Lambda and would like to share his findings with the
community.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-10-26:2017-oct-meetup.html</guid><category>machine learning</category><category>cloud</category></item><item><title>Notification of PUGS AGM 2017</title><link>/2017-AGM-notice.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dear PUGS members,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be holding our Annual General Meeting on Tuesday, October 31 from 7 to
9pm at Red Hat Singapore office (8 Shenton Way, 10-01 AXA Tower, Singapore
068811, &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/HADBLmgHsVt"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an election year. We will select and vote among those present at the AGM
on who will be on the new Executive committee, as well as ordinary committee
members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick history of PUGS and activities during 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation of Financial Accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Election of the new Executive committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon-APAC 2018 in Singapore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join us if you are interested in shaping local Python users community.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-10-09:2017-AGM-notice.html</guid></item><item><title>September 2017 meetup</title><link>/2017-sep-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date:&lt;/em&gt; September 26, 7 to 9pm&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Venue:&lt;/em&gt; Carousell, Keppel Tower 2, Tanjong Pagar Road&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Signup:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/240954690/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7pm: Meet &amp;amp; Greet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30pm: Talk #1: Using Kivy to Write an iOS and Android App by Chao-Jen Chen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract:&lt;/em&gt;
Kivy is an open source Python framework that allows developers to write apps for
and run the same code on Linux, Windows, Mac OS X, iOS, and Android. I will walk
through an end-to-end process, from coding an app using Kivy library to
deploying the same app to iOS and Android devices using Kivy toolchains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio&lt;/em&gt;:
Chao-Jen Chen is a university instructor teaching Calculus, Probability, and
Linear Algebra. He used to work in the finance industry as fixed income
quantitative analyst and FX manager, managing and hedging USD3bn FX exposure to
more than 20 currencies. His personal research interest is Singapore’s monetary
policy tool, i.e., the SGD NEER (Singapore Dollar Nominal Effective Exchange
Rate). In April 2017, he released an app in Google Play and Apple App Store that
implemented his SGD NEER model. He also wrote a chapter on numerical computing
in finance for a book (F# Deep Dives, published by Manning Publications Co. in
December, 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update 2017-10-09: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Chao-Jen/Kivy_example_for_PUGS_Sep_2017"&gt;code example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8pm: Talk #2: Welcome to async/await by Dima Tisnek&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/dimaqq"&gt;Dima&lt;/a&gt; will present the paradigm of async/await across a few languages (Python3.6
and ES2017) with some live coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1i6UvGNN11q9IaFIa1qV_xl52cjNuH-qUcl0MPX0_vao/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="https://carousell.com"&gt;Carousell&lt;/a&gt; for the food and venue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-10-04:2017-sep-meetup.html</guid><category>GUI</category><category>dev-practice</category></item><item><title>August 2017 meetup</title><link>/2017-aug-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date:&lt;/em&gt; August 29, 7 to 9pm&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Venue:&lt;/em&gt; Singapore Power, Keppel Tower 2 #08-00, Tanjong Pagar Road&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Signup:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/240986696/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7pm: Meet &amp;amp; Greet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30pm: Talk #1: Predicting Singapore House price and rents with linear regression and neural network using URA property transaction data by Vikrant Rathore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/v/1954"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract:&lt;/em&gt;
I recently moved to a new home. While looking for a home I checked
propertyguru.com and 99.co, two most common place to look for buy/sell or rent
property in Singapore. But while looking at them I wanted to see if the asking
price is in-line with the actual value of the house or not. As URA (Urban
Renewal Authority) in Singapore compiles the property transaction data
(available as realis paid subscription or free with limited information). Based
on this data I thought of writing python prgram to see if can leverage machine
learning or deep learning to to train linear regression model using URA data and
predict the price based on location and size of the house and compare it with
asking price. In this attempt to write the program I trained linear regression
model using various algorithms like Elastic Net, Random Forest and linear
regression with single layer and multi-layer neural network using tensorflow.
Later compared them and then used the model to predict unseen data. In this talk
I will walk you through the journey of how I tried doing step by step using
jupyter notebook, pandas, numpy, scipy, tensorflow, keras, matplotlib. You will
see the challenges of handling categorical data for linear regression which
prefer numerical data and some of the ways to avoid over-fitting or
under-fitting. Consider it like a primer on machine learning for house
price/rental prediction for Singapore property transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio&lt;/em&gt;:
Vikrant Rathore is technology professional and an entrepreneur at heart with
interest in Startups and Innovative Technology. With over 20 years of working
experience in Asia, USA and Europe, at present working on his own Startup
Komerco which is his attempt to organize global product information for
multi-channel commerce. In this endeavor leveraging Python and its excellent
libraries. Previously in China while working for arvato systems (part of
Bertelsmann, one of the largest media and services group in Europe), he helped
many multi-nationals for digital transformation and direct to consumer strategy.
He also worked with Bayer in APAC region to launch their sales force
effectiveness and customer relationship management program targeting healthcare
professionals like doctors, nurses and hospitals. In his current work whenever
necessary he leverages machine and deep learning to make decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8pm: Talk #2: Introduction to BeeWare by Paul Lorett Amazona&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="https://github.com/whatevergeek/presentations/tree/master/201708/intro_to_beeware-toga"&gt;slides &amp;amp;
code&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/v/1955"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: 
Toga is Python native, OS native GUI toolkit. It allows one to develop an app in
Python and deploy it as a native implementation in various platforms. Paul (who
recently attended Pycon AU 2017) will be sharing his experience in one if the
conference sprints where he contributed to the development of a toga widget. If
time allows, he'll demo an app written in python and deployed in a number of
platforms (e.g. windows, linux, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio&lt;/em&gt;:
Paul is a developer who enjoys polyglot development. He uses .NET and Microsoft
Dev stack at work. Outside work, he uses other languages such as Python and R
for non-profit initiatives and various personal IoT projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.spgroup.com.sg"&gt;SP&lt;/a&gt; for the food and venue
and &lt;a href="https://engineers.sg"&gt;Engineers.SG&lt;/a&gt; for recording the event!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-08-29:2017-aug-meetup.html</guid><category>machine learning</category><category>GUI</category></item><item><title>July 2017 meetup</title><link>/2017-jul-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date:&lt;/em&gt; July 6, 7 to 9pm&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Venue:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.zendesk.com/"&gt;Zendesk&lt;/a&gt;, 401 Commonwealth Drive Haw Par Technocentre, #07-01
(&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/NNHUz"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Signup:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/239748794/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7pm: Meet &amp;amp; Greet&lt;/strong&gt;
While everyone arrives, we have the chance to chat and mingle, Zendesk is kindly
sponsoring snacks and soft-drinks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30pm: Talk #1: Deep Learning with Python in Finance by Ben Ball&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract:&lt;/em&gt; Python is becoming the de facto standard for many machine learning
applications. We have been using Python with deep learning and other ML
techniques, with a focus in prediction and exploitation in transactional
markets. I am presenting one of our implementations (A dueling double DQN - a
class of Reinforcement Learning algorithm) in Python using TensorFlow, along
with information and background around the class of deep learning algorithm, and
the application to financial markets we have employed. Attendees will learn how
to implement a DQN using Tensorflow, and how to design a system for deep
learning for solving a wide range of problems. The code will be available on
github for attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio&lt;/em&gt;: Ben is a believer in making a career out of what you love. He is inspired
by the joining of excellent technology and research and likes building software
that is easy to use, but does amazing things. His work has spanned 15 years,
with a dual focus in AI Software Engineering and Algorithmic Trading. He is
currently working as the CTO of &lt;a href="http://prediction-machines.com"&gt;http://prediction-machines.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8pm: Talk #2: Introduction to MicroPython - Mighty Python Running on Tiny
Embedded Boards by Ovidiu Hossu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: Coming soon! Hardware-hackers listen up! Ovidiu will give an
introduction to MicroPython and bring a few of his boards to run some real-world
demos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.zendesk.com/"&gt;Zendesk&lt;/a&gt; for hosting us once again 
and &lt;a href="https://engineers.sg"&gt;Engineers.SG&lt;/a&gt; for recording the event!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://prediction-machines.com/2017/07/07/deeprl-with-python-tensorflow/"&gt;Ben's talk and github repos&lt;/a&gt;
    (&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/v/1875"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/OvidiuHOSSU1/micropython-introduction-pusg-july-2017"&gt;Ovidiu's talk&lt;/a&gt;
    (&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/v/1874"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="July meetup attendees" src="/img/2017-jul-meetup.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-06-06:2017-jul-meetup.html</guid><category>machine learning</category><category>hardware</category></item><item><title>May 2017 meetup</title><link>/2017-may-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;It's Slack time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have a slack channel open to everybody. You can join at
&lt;a href="https://pugs-org-sg-slackin.now.sh/"&gt;https://pugs-org-sg-slackin.now.sh/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;May meetup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next PUGS meetup is planned for May 31, from 7 to 9pm at
&lt;a href="https://www.zendesk.com/"&gt;Zendesk&lt;/a&gt;, 401 Commonwealth Drive Haw Par Technocentre, #07-01
(&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/NNHUz"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSVP at the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/239748794/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="goo.gl/ZEGcY2"&gt;Pyfrost talk slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/1Qys5Z"&gt;Photos from the event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7pm: Meet &amp;amp; Greet. While everyone arrives, we have the chance to chat and
mingle, Zendesk is kindly sponsoring snacks and soft-drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7:30pm: Talk #1: &lt;strong&gt;Pyfrost: microservice for feature gating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: Pyfrost is a microservice that aims to solve all your feature gating
needs. The philosophy behind pyfrost is to think of entitlement of features you
develop as a logical conclusion of various considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio&lt;/em&gt;:Yatish Bathini has been working as a software engineer on the live chat
product offered by Zendesk (formerly known as Zopim) since 2015. He is an
integral part of the team working on developing key product features for
enterprise markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8pm: Talk #2: &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Algorithmic Trading With Quantopian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: In this short sharing session, Anthony will walk you through the
&lt;a href="https://www.quantopian.com"&gt;Quantopian&lt;/a&gt; platform and explain the data, tools,
lectures and various aids provided to get you from a novice to professional algo
developer. You will learn how to utilise the back tester to test your algo
strategy and when you are happy with it, go live and trade with real money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio&lt;/em&gt;: Anthony has been teaching investment and portfolio management related
modules at educational institutions since 2010. He holds an MBA and an MFE from
Otago University (NZ) and NUS (Singapore) respectively. With a strong passion
for finance, data science, and programming, Anthony has also designed
curriculums for his own beginner level algorithmic trading workshops in addition
to Quantopian events.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-05-06:2017-may-meetup.html</guid><category>dev-practice</category></item><item><title>March 2017 meetup</title><link>/2017-mar-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The next PUGS meetup is planned for March 29, from 7 to 9pm at the new
&lt;a href="https://pivotal.io/"&gt;Pivotal&lt;/a&gt; office (140 Robinson Rd, Singapore 068907, #16-00,
&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/140+Robinson+Rd,+Singapore+068907/@1.2783023,103.8473368,18z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x31da19125ce3bdd5:0x129471cdbaefa494!8m2!3d1.2783342!4d103.8482807"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;).
(Note: Please have an ID with you for building security check).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSVP at the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/238107286/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt; (and please unRSVP if you can't make it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Talk&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/v/1617"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/lihaoyi/opendata"&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploring Singapore's Open Data APIs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract:&lt;/em&gt; Open data is data that is available to anyone, without fee, copyright,
or restrictions on usage, and Singapore is one of many governments that have
started providing open data feeds. This talk will explore the use of open data
from a developers point of view, and show the possibilities and limitations when
dealing with Singapore's Open Data APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio:&lt;/em&gt; Haoyi is a software engineer, previously working at Dropbox, currently
working on a developer tools startup in Singapore. He's interested in
programming languages, developer productivity, web development, and automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-03-15:2017-mar-meetup.html</guid><category>analytics</category></item><item><title>February 2017 meetup</title><link>/2017-feb-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The next PUGS meetup is planned for February 22, from 7 to 9pm at the new
&lt;a href="https://carousell.com"&gt;Carousell&lt;/a&gt; office (&lt;a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=240+Tanjong+Pagar+Road+%2312-00%2C+088540%2C+sg"&gt;Carousell@Keppel Towers
2&lt;/a&gt;,
240 Tanjong Pagar Road #12-00, 088540).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSVP on the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/237386331/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Talk&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/O4yd0W"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/v/1416"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lua for Python developers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: In this introduction to Lua I'll demonstrate the essentials of Lua
and compare them with Python. I'll also introduce you to how Nmap Scripting
Engine uses Lua, and will walk you around some of the important libraries it
ships with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speaker&lt;/em&gt;: Gyanendra Mishra is a Computer Science senior at BITS Pilani, India.
Currently he is in Singapore as a research intern at the Singapore University of
Technology and Design working for the betterment of the security of Cyber
Physical Systems. He loves to work on random projects in Python. In 2015 he
participated in the Google Summer of Code Project under Nmap Security Scanner
where he  got introduced to Lua.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2017-02-13:2017-feb-meetup.html</guid><category>dev-practice</category></item><item><title>Notification of PUGS AGM 2016</title><link>/2016-oct-agm-announce.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dear PUGS members,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be holding our Annual General Meeting on Tuesday, October 25 from 7 to
9pm at Red Hat Singapore office (8 Shenton Way, 10-01 AXA Tower, Singapore
068811,
&lt;a href="https://encrypted.google.com/maps/place/Red+Hat/@1.275445,103.8469478,18z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x166080ad6b7de256!8m2!3d1.2757561!4d103.8472804?hl=en"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation of Financial Accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PyCon-APAC 2017 in Kuala Lumpur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activities for 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join us if you are interested in shaping local Python communities. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2016-10-09:2016-oct-agm-announce.html</guid></item><item><title>July 2016 meetup</title><link>/2016-jul-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[postfactum]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Talk&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear no evil, see no evil, patch no evil: Or, how to monkey-patch safely&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;a href="http://www.dscpl.com.au"&gt;Graham Dumpleton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a dynamic programming language and has a strong tradition of adhering
to a programming style called duck-typing. This means that it is possible to
easily modify an application's code while it is running. One might wish to do
this for various reasons, including enhancing the functionality of code,
correcting errant behaviour, or adding instrumentation or debugging code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making such code modifications can be tricky though and not done correctly can
potentially interfere with the operation of the original code, through
destroying introspection abilities, not honouring the duck-typing mantra or due
to being applied at the wrong time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do need to do monkey patching though, the 'wrapt' library is your friend,
with its transparent object proxy wrappers and post import hook mechanism, it
allows you to safely monkey patch code to modify its behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come learn about the 'wrapt' library and the joys, but also the dangers, of
monkey patching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speaker&lt;/em&gt;: Graham is the author of mod_wsgi, a popular module for hosting
Python web applications with the Apache HTTPD web server. He has a keen
interest in Docker and Platform as a Service (PaaS) technologies, and is a
Fellow of the Python Software Foundation and Member of the Apache Software
Foundation. He is currently a developer advocate for OpenShift at Red Hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/232538900/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/video/hear-no-evil-see-no-evil-patch-no-evil-singapore-python-user-group--911"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; (thanks &lt;a href="https://engineers.sg"&gt;engineers.sg&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to &lt;a href="https://www.paypal.com/sg"&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt; for hosting.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2016-09-07:2016-jul-meetup.html</guid><category>dev-practice</category></item><item><title>Thank You for Attending PyCon SG 2016</title><link>/2016-pyconsg-thank-you.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mbrochh/27912517782/in/album-72157670466796255/"&gt;&lt;img alt="PyConSG 2016 attendees" src="/img/2016-pyconsg-crowd.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organizing committee would like to thank everyone for coming to PyCon
Singapore 2016. This year we had over 250 participants! This conference is only
possible because of your interest! Here are some
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mbrochh/sets/72157670466796255"&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; of the
conference. And if you’ve missed a talk in a parallel session, you may want to
look for it in &lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/conference/pyconsg2016"&gt;video recordings&lt;/a&gt;,
courtesy of &lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/"&gt;enginners.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to all the speakers and tutorial instructors. We are very happy
to see a growing number of women presenting their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to our keynote speakers Daniel and Audrey Roy Greenfeld and Yves
J. Hilpisch for coming all the way to Singapore, and sharing your knowledge and
experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we were lucky again to have &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mbrochh/27734611480/in/album-72157670466796255/"&gt;student volunteers and Mr.
Gi&lt;/a&gt;
from &lt;a href="http://www.dhs.sg/"&gt;Dunman High School&lt;/a&gt;. Your help is invaluable for
ensuring a smooth conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to thank &lt;a href="http://www.comp.nus.edu.sg"&gt;NUS School of Computing&lt;/a&gt;
for providing the venue and wifi access to all participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we would like to thank all our sponsors; &lt;em&gt;platinum&lt;/em&gt;:
&lt;a href="http://corporate.garena.com"&gt;Garena&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pivotal.io"&gt;Pivotal&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://www.quantopian.com"&gt;Quantopian&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;em&gt;gold&lt;/em&gt;:
&lt;a href="https://www.airbnb.com"&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://bitmazk.com"&gt;Bitmazk&lt;/a&gt;; and
&lt;em&gt;silver&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://carousell.com"&gt;Carousell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://theartling.com"&gt;The
Artling&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://jublia.com"&gt;Jublia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.acronis.com/en-sg/"&gt;Acronis&lt;/a&gt;.
They are all hiring. If you’d like to contact them, let us know, and we can put
you in touch with relevant people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for feedback from our attendees so that we can take the
conference to the next level in the coming years.
A short &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1WdsXPBMncDe4aFyvhIYrzb8OekOdPAbd0Oy1N_J6go4/edit?uiv=1"&gt;feedback form&lt;/a&gt;
is available online which will not take you more than five minutes to complete.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2016-07-07:2016-pyconsg-thank-you.html</guid><category>pyconsg</category></item><item><title>May 2016 meetups</title><link>/2016-may-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;PyData meetup happened on May 10. The topic was "Using Luigi and Scikit-Learn to
create a Machine Learning Pipeline which trains a model and predict through a Rest API" by Atreya Biswas
(&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/PyData-SG/events/227687789/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/video/a-machine-learning-data-pipeline-pydata-sg--723"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PUGS meeting is on May 25th at &lt;a href="https://carousell.com"&gt;Carousell&lt;/a&gt;,
71 Ayer Rajah Crescent, #03-14 Singapore 139951, Singapore (
&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/71+Ayer+Rajah+Crescent,+Singapore+139951/@1.2967417,103.7844749,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x31da1a4fd6a29643:0x1cbb8a56dd8c9ccf!8m2!3d1.2967417!4d103.7866636?hl=en"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;
).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSVP &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/230569164/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://carousell.com"&gt;Carousell&lt;/a&gt; for the venue, pizzas and drinks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing a Serverless Python Microservice with AWS Lambda by &lt;a href="http://dchua.com"&gt;David Chua&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Synopsis:&lt;/em&gt; Want to run a Serverless Microservice? What is Serverless? In this short
little introduction I'll demonstrate how to get a quick python microservice
out from scratch into the cloud and never have to worry about infrastructure
scaling ever again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bio&lt;/em&gt;: David is a former Rubyist with strong inclination towards the
infrastructure/backend side whom has joined the Dark Side about 2 months ago.
He is looking forward to learning and contributing to the amazing PUGS
community. In a former life, he run a digital consultancy but now works for &lt;a href="https://99.co"&gt;https://99.co&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="http://dchua.com/2016/03/22/writing-a-serverless-python-microservice-with-aws-lambda-and-aws-api-gateway/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/davidchua/passlib_lambda"&gt;passlib repo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/davidchua/seng_bot"&gt;telegram bot repo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update on &lt;a href="https://pycon.sg"&gt;PyConSG&lt;/a&gt; which is happening next month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2016-05-24:2016-may-meetup.html</guid><category>cloud</category><category>devops</category></item><item><title>Apr 2016 meetups</title><link>/2016-apr-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;April PyData meetup is on April 12. The topic is &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/PyData-SG/events/227687774/"&gt;Sentiment Analysis using
Stanford's CoreNLP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PUGS meeting is on April 18th at &lt;a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=5+Temasek+Blvd%2C+%2309-01+Suntec+Tower+Five%2C+038985%2C+Singapore%2C+sg"&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt;
(5 Temasek Blvd, #09-01 Suntec Tower Five, 038985, Singapore). RSVP &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/229604322/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to PayPal for the venue, pizzas and drinks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinforcement learning using Python by Joe Le Truc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Synopsis&lt;/em&gt;: Reinforcement learning is at the heart of modern AI techniques.
In this talk, I will survey the the main ideas of reinforcement learning and
introduce ‘Smartcab’ -- simulation of a self-driving car from the
not-so-distant future. The application is developed using Python and the
Pygame framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fJPmHzDFc9SYykhgZIRH-ZovdRat6cHJOBNG4CzTA60/edit#slide=id.p"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/video/reinforcement-learning-using-python-python-sg--678"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python for RPi Sense HAT by Paul Lorett B. Amazona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Synopsis&lt;/em&gt;:  The Sense HAT is an add-on board for Raspberry Pi, made
especially for the Astro Pi mission -- went to the International Space
Station in December 2015. The Sense HAT has an 8×8 RGB LED matrix, a
five-button joystick and includes a number of sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/whatevergeek/PUGS-SenseHAT-Demo"&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://engineers.sg/video/python-for-rpi-sense-hat-python-sg--677"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2016-04-01:2016-apr-meetup.html</guid><category>machine learning</category><category>hardware</category></item><item><title>Mar 2016 meetup</title><link>/2016-mar-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Incredible turnout at yesterday's meetup.
Some pictures are &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/photos/26801990/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Big thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.redhat.com/en/global/singapore"&gt;Red Hat Singapore&lt;/a&gt; for hosting us.
Another big thanks to semi-anonymous pizza sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sayan.ee/"&gt;Sayanee&lt;/a&gt; went through some cool stats from
   &lt;a href="https://data.webuild.sg/"&gt;https://data.webuild.sg/&lt;/a&gt; showing how vibrant and diverse Singapore's
   developers scene is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ivan's &lt;a href="http://vanzaj.github.io/tdd-pytest/"&gt;TDD with pytest&lt;/a&gt; "translation"
   project is hopefully more useful than slides. Pull requests are very welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin showed that it is now possible to integrate ReactJS with a new or
   an existing Django project without too much pain. His boilerplate repo is
   &lt;a href="https://github.com/mbrochh/django-reactjs-boilerplate"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2016-03-10:2016-mar-meetup.html</guid><category>dev-practice</category><category>webdev</category><category>community</category></item><item><title>Call for proposals for PyConSG 2016</title><link>/2016-pyconsg-call-for-talks.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pycon.sg/"&gt;PyCon Singapore 2016&lt;/a&gt; is happening again! Mark your calendars
for June 23 to 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again we've got the support of great keynote speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel and Audrey Greenfeld (&lt;a href="https://www.twoscoopspress.com"&gt;Two Scoops of Django&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.djangopackages.com/"&gt;Django Packages&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Yves J. Hilpisch (&lt;a href="http://tpq.io/"&gt;The Python Quants&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://python-for-finance.com/"&gt;Python for Finance (O'Reilly 2014)&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have some awesome talks lined up, given by developers of the local
community on subjects like web development, devops, CS education, and data
analytics. However, we still have many slots available.  Whether you're a
seasoned pro, or a beginner who has an interesting story to tell, we welcome all
proposals for technical talks of about 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To submit a talk, please register at &lt;a href="https://pycon.sg/proposals/"&gt;https://pycon.sg/proposals/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closing date for proposals is 30th April 2016, but we'd appreciate it if you
can submit your idea earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to get in touch via email, ping us at conference(at)pycon.sg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't wait! We're looking forward to receiving your submissions! We should also
mention that for the first time we will grant a 25% rebate on the conference
ticket for speakers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2016-01-29:2016-pyconsg-call-for-talks.html</guid><category>pyconsg</category></item><item><title>Nov 2015 meetup</title><link>/2015-nov-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Next user meeting will be held on the 27th of November from 7pm to 9pm at the
PayPal office (5 Temasek Blvd, Suntec Tower Five, Level 7, 038985, &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=5+Temasek+Blvd%2C+Suntec+Tower+Five%2C+Level+7%2C+038985%2C+sg"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;).
RSVP at the &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Singapore-Python-User-Group/events/226392762/"&gt;meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce the new PUGS committee members and a word of appreciation for the
    old exco, Victor and his team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss PUGS events for the upcoming year (people are welcome to come over and
    request for training and stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss PyConSG 2016 conference content and committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impromptu lightning talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post meeting update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2015 nov topics" src="/img/2015-nov-meetup-topics.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to those who attended our PUGS Meetup last Friday!  It was a fruitful
information session and with suggestions from the community for content ranging
from suggested topics for courses and talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 101 and Python 102 courses (preferably on the weekend)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Programming in Python in various Web Frameworks e.g.Django, Flask&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rasberry Pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Analytics and Data Manipulation in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get hired with Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison of Languages e.g. Java vs Scala vs Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was popular demand for our meetups to be once a month to maintain
consistency and community involvement. In addition, we have a couple of
volunteers for the PyCon next year. We will be arranging for the PyCon Committee
to meet up soon.  We will start planning out the Python 101 and 102 course and
use the other interested topics as content for subsequent meetups.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2015-11-20:2015-nov-meetup.html</guid></item><item><title>Thank You for Attending PyCon SG 2015</title><link>/2015-pyconsg-thank-you.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mbrochh/18786975678/"&gt;&lt;img alt="PyConSG 2015 attendees" src="/img/2015-pyconsg-crowd.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of all the PyCon organizing committee members, I would like to thank
everyone for their support for PyCon Singapore 2015 which was held
at &lt;a href="http://www.sp.edu.sg/"&gt;Singapore Polytechnic&lt;/a&gt; from 17th June to 19th June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This marks the 6th conference to be organized by the Python User Group
Community in Singapore and we hope that your feedback and support will help us
improve and take the conference to the next level in the coming years. A short
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1NOurBthP6AeRhYq2xH9uOirGAaQPH6tNvRJoISnZkXU/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;feedback form&lt;/a&gt;
is available online which will not take you more than five minutes
to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the efforts of Ivan and Mr Gi, along with the support of the Ministry of
Education Singapore, the first EDU Summit was successfully held on the first
day of the conference. The summit brought together Computing and Computer
Science educators from O-levels to tertiary institutions to share their
teaching experiences and upcoming changes to the computing curriculum for O and
A levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be updating this blog post with links to slide decks once we receive
them from the speakers. Keep a lookout for them either via this blog post or
our Twitter account. Our friends from engineers.sg have also recorded videos of
talks during this conference and these videos will also be viewable online once
they are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon SG 2015 would not have been possible without the tremendous support we
have received from our sponsors and volunteers. I would like to thank our
sponsors, &lt;a href="http://www.sp.edu.sg"&gt;Singapore Polytechnic&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://www.braintreepayments.com/"&gt;Braintree&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://neo.com"&gt;Neo&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://bitmazk.com"&gt;Bitmazk&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://carousell.com"&gt;Carousell&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com"&gt;ThoughtWorks&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/"&gt;Python Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://mysql.com"&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt; for supporting the community and making this
conference possible. Student helpers and their teacher, Mr Gi, from
&lt;a href="http://www.dhs.sg/"&gt;Dunman High School&lt;/a&gt; played a huge role in ensuring that
the conference ran smoothly. Special thanks go out to our keynote speakers
Andrew Godwin, Jessica McKellar and Lynn Root for their inspirational keynotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, as the chair of this conference, I would like to thank the
organizing committee for all their hard work in the past year to make this
conference a reality. We will soon be opening a call for volunteers for
PyCon SG 2016; if you are interested in helping out with the conference (no
technical chops required), look out for our next meeting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely, Victor Neo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairman, PyCon Singapore 2015&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2015-06-22:2015-pyconsg-thank-you.html</guid><category>pyconsg</category></item><item><title>Apr 2015 meetup</title><link>/2015-apr-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Next user meeting will be held on the 30th of April from 7pm to 9pm at the
&lt;a href="http://hackerspace.sg"&gt;hackerspace.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How I built a SFTP service using Paramiko" by Steve (&lt;a href="https://github.com/lonetwin/paramiko_talk"&gt;slides on github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bOPa6Sj3XAQ"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Python tips: Packing and Unpacking" by Shubham (&lt;a href="http://nbviewer.ipython.org/github/shubhamgoyal/Python-User-Group-Singapore-PUGS-Talks/blob/master/April%202015%20Meetup/Python%20Tips%20and%20Tricks.ipynb"&gt;notebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E3Y74_JhuJk"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2015-04-24:2015-apr-meetup.html</guid><category>dev-practice</category><category>motm</category></item><item><title>Call for proposals for PyConSG 2015</title><link>/2015-pyconsg-call-for-talks.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The organizing committee for &lt;a href="https://pycon.sg/"&gt;PyCon Singapore 2015&lt;/a&gt; would like to invite members
of the global Python community to submit talk proposals and tutorial proposals
for our conference happening at the &lt;a href="http://www.sp.edu.sg/"&gt;Singapore Polytechnic&lt;/a&gt;
from 17-19 June 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again we've got the support of great keynote speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Godwin (Django core developer, creator of South)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica McKellar (OpenHatch, Twisted, Python Software Foundation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lynn Root (Spotify, PyLadies, Python Software Foundation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have some awesome talks lined up, given by developers of the local
community, on everything from web development, to infrastructure, to API
development. However, we still have many slots available and would really love
to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you're a seasoned pro, or a beginner who has an interesting story to
tell, we welcome all proposals for technical talks of about 30-40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To submit a talk, please register at &lt;a href="https://pycon.sg/proposals/"&gt;https://pycon.sg/proposals/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closing date for proposals is 30th April 2015, but we'd appreciate it if you
can submit your idea earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to get in touch via email, ping us at conference(at)pycon.sg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't wait! We're looking forward to receiving your submissions! We should also
mention that for the first time we will grant a 25% rebate on the conference
ticket for speakers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2015-02-26:2015-pyconsg-call-for-talks.html</guid><category>pyconsg</category></item><item><title>Feb 2015 meetup</title><link>/2015-feb-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Next regular user meeting is scheduled for February 26 at 7pm at &lt;a href="https://www.paypal.com/sg/"&gt;PayPal
Singapore&lt;/a&gt; (UPDATE: at Millenia Office), 1 Temasek
Avenue, Millenia Tower, #14-01.  Our friendly hosts have graciously offered to
provide pizzas and drinks! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kokhong Cheng - virtualenv in the enterprise environment
  (&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/-XgYrGzzfFI"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martijn Faassen - &lt;a href="https://github.com/morepath/morepath"&gt;MorePath&lt;/a&gt; and
  &lt;a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/index.html"&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
  Update: the central theme of my talk is going to be hypermedia, 
  in both APIs and UIs. Morepath was designed to let you build hypermedia APIs 
  (aka REST APIs), and I'll go into some of the whys and hows and future 
  directions (&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/eWd7zlM77oo"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2015-01-17:2015-feb-meetup.html</guid><category>webdev</category><category>devops</category></item><item><title>Jan 2015 events</title><link>/2014-dec-announce.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First &lt;a href="https://facebook.com/groups/pydatasg/"&gt;PyData SG&lt;/a&gt; meetup will
happen on January 15, 2015 from 7 to 9:30pm at &lt;a href="http://www.spire.com/"&gt;Spire
Global&lt;/a&gt;, Red Dot Traffic building (#04-07, 28 Maxwell Rd, 
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/Xhpl6"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five talks (10-20 min each) are already lined up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thia Kai Xin: Optimization models (&lt;a href="http://nbviewer.ipython.org/gist/thiakx/73c328f00aac0fbf6075"&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Andrews: Theano (&amp;amp; GPUs) (&lt;a href="http://redcatlabs.com/2015-01-15_Presentation-PyDataSG/"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asankhaya Sharma: Software security analytics (&lt;a href="http://asankhaya.github.io/ppt/PyDataSing.pptx"&gt;pptx&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shubham Goyal/Girish Kumar: Introduction to scikit-learn (&lt;a href="https://github.com/shubhamgoyal/PyData1"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eugene Teo: Spyre (&lt;a href="http://nbviewer.ipython.org/github/eugeneteo/pydatasg-spyre/blob/master/slides/pydatasg-spyre.ipynb"&gt;nbviewer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/994351117258134/"&gt;Event page on FB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated 2015-01-15: Added links to presentations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2014-12-13:2014-dec-announce.html</guid><category>analytics</category><category>pydata</category></item><item><title>Sep 2014 meetup</title><link>/2014-sep-meeting.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[postfactum]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An irregular&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt; user meeting was held on September 4th, 7:30-9pm at 
&lt;a href="http://hackerspace.sg"&gt;HSG&lt;/a&gt; as usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/gaqzi"&gt;Björn&lt;/a&gt; talked about Reusable Django Apps among other
things (&lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/gaqzi/reusable-django-apps"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;───&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt; Thanks to PayPal for pizza and beers. Hopefully this irregularity
will become part of our regular user meetings... &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2014-09-08:2014-sep-meeting.html</guid><category>webdev</category></item><item><title>July 2014 events</title><link>/2014-jul-meetings.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/PyLadies-SG/events/193896182/"&gt;PyLadies SG&lt;/a&gt; are
organizing "Introduction to Python" tutorial on July 26th, 1-4pm at
&lt;a href="http://hackerspace.sg"&gt;HSG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next regular PUGS meeting will be held on July 31th, 7-9pm at
&lt;a href="http://hackerspace.sg"&gt;HSG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New stuff in &lt;a href="http://ipython.org/notebook.html"&gt;IPython notebook&lt;/a&gt;: widgets
   and alternative visualization by Ivan (&lt;a href="https://github.com/vanzaj/pytalks/tree/master/20140731_PUGS_ipython"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/1zPoNHW"&gt;html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data mining, NLP and graph analysis with
   &lt;a href="http://www.clips.ua.ac.be/pages/pattern"&gt;pattern&lt;/a&gt; by Rahul
(&lt;a href="https://github.com/rahulg/ipython-notebooks"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/1ontws2"&gt;html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2014-07-21:2014-jul-meetings.html</guid><category>analytics</category><category>visualisation</category></item><item><title>Thank You for Attending PyCon SG 2014</title><link>/2014-pyconsg-thank-you.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mbrochh/14465517992/"&gt;&lt;img alt="PyConSG 2014 attendees" src="/img/2014-pyconsg-crowd.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of all the PyCon organizing committee members, I would like to thank
all attendees for taking time off to attend PyCon Singapore 2014 which was held at
&lt;a href="http://www.sp.edu.sg/"&gt;Singapore Polytechnic&lt;/a&gt; from 18th June to 20th June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We organized this conference for the Python developer and student community in
Singapore and we are very grateful for your support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your feedback regarding the conference will be critical in order for the
organizing committee to make PyCon SG 2015 even better than this year's
conference. A short &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1A5NoxhvrD2mnrT47b88LKjng63v3kZfT6smDOSc5rAk/viewform"&gt;feedback form&lt;/a&gt;
is available online which shall not take more than five minutes to
complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have requested all speakers of the conference to send us links or PDF copies
of their slide decks. For those of you who are eager to view them, do look out
for updates on &lt;a href="https://pycon.sg/news/2014/6/21/slides/"&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;
which will be updated as as we receive the slide decks from the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conference would not have been possible without the tremendous support we
have received. I would like to thank our sponsors, &lt;a href="http://www.sp.edu.sg"&gt;Singapore
Polytechnic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.heroku.com/"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.odd-e.com/"&gt;Odd-e&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.zopim.com/"&gt;Zopim&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.oracle.com/"&gt;Oracle&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://continuum.io/"&gt;Continuum
Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, as well as Mr Gi and student helpers from
&lt;a href="http://www.dhs.sg/"&gt;Dunman High School&lt;/a&gt; who played a huge role in ensuring that
the conference ran smoothly. Special thanks go out to our keynote speakers David
Cramer and Kenneth Reitz for flying down all the way from US to inspire us with
their keynotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as the chair of this conference, I would like to thank the organizing
committee for all their hard work in the past year to make this conference a
reality. In the coming weeks, we will be holding a meeting to elect the
organizing committee for PyCon SG 2015. If you are interested in joining the
PyCon 2015 committee, you may let us know on the feedback form above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,
Victor Neo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairman, PyCon Singapore 2014&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2014-06-24:2014-pyconsg-thank-you.html</guid><category>pyconsg</category></item><item><title>Call for proposals for PyConSG 2014</title><link>/2014-pyconsg-call-for-talks.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the organizing committee of PyCon SG 2014,
we are pleased to invite members of the community to submit talks
and/or tutorials for the 2014 PyCon Singapore Conference, to be held at the &lt;a href="http://www.sp.edu.sg/"&gt;Singapore Polytechnic&lt;/a&gt; from June 18 to 20, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our highlight this year is the announcement of 2 keynote speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kennethreitz.org/about/"&gt;Kenneth Reitz&lt;/a&gt; - product owner of Python at 
   &lt;a href="https://www.heroku.com"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; and author of the &lt;a href="http://docs.python-requests.org/en/latest/"&gt;Requests&lt;/a&gt; library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://justcramer.com/"&gt;David Cramer&lt;/a&gt; - Engineer at &lt;a href="http://dropbox.com"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; and founder of &lt;a href="https://www.getsentry.com"&gt;Sentry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk and Tutorial submission details can be found at &lt;a href="https://pycon.sg/proposals/"&gt;https://pycon.sg/proposals/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The submission deadline for both is April 30, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For enquiries, please direct them to conference(at)pycon.sg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to receiving your submissions and to a great
conference this year!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2014-02-17:2014-pyconsg-call-for-talks.html</guid><category>pyconsg</category></item><item><title>Feb 2014 meetup</title><link>/2014-feb-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Next user meeting will be held on February 19th, 7:30-9pm at the
&lt;a href="http://hackerspace.sg"&gt;hackerspace.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll have &lt;a href="http://startifact.com/"&gt;Martijn Faassen&lt;/a&gt; presenting on
&lt;a href="https://github.com/morepath/morepath"&gt;MorePath&lt;/a&gt; micro web framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Morepath is an Python WSGI microframework. It uses routing, but the routing
is to models. Morepath is model-driven and flexible, which makes it
expressive." (&lt;a href="http://morepath.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2014-01-27:2014-feb-meetup.html</guid><category>webdev</category></item><item><title>Dec 2013 meetup</title><link>/2013-dec-meetup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Next user meeting will be held on December 18th, 7-9pm at the new
&lt;a href="http://hackerspace.sg"&gt;hackerspace.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the menu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps with Python (&lt;a href="http://www.ansibleworks.com/"&gt;ansible&lt;/a&gt;) by Rahul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building interactive web based data visualizations on large
datasets without writing any javascript! (&lt;a href="http://bokeh.pydata.org/"&gt;bokeh&lt;/a&gt;) by Hugo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos (thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/coderkungfu"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wLQULGdqx9c&amp;amp;list=PLECEw2eFfW7hYMucZmsrryV_9nIc485P1"&gt;Rahul's talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQHHVhsdqOc&amp;amp;list=PLECEw2eFfW7hYMucZmsrryV_9nIc485P1"&gt;Hugo's talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ivan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:,2013-11-29:2013-dec-meetup.html</guid><category>devops</category><category>visualisation</category></item></channel></rss>